《星际迷航6: 未来之城》
星历9521.6
Stardate 9521.6.
船长日志 上进号由苏路指挥
Captain's log U.S.S. Excelsior. Hikaru Sulu commanding.
我首次完成叁年的船长任务
After three years I've concluded my first assignment as master of this vessel
记载第二区的气体反常现象
cataloguing gaseous planetary anomalies in Beta Quadrant.
我们正全速返回基地
We're heading home under full impulse power.
太空船和船员一切正常
I'm pleased to report that ship and crew have functioned well.
我们己完成全区的调查工作
According to this,we've completed our survey of the entire sector.
这里有强度240的能量流
I have an energy wave at 240 degrees mark six port.
看
Visual!
天
My... God!
快开防护罩
Shields. Shields!
太空船没有反应
She's not answering her helm.
右边推进器 转入气流中
Starboard thrusters. Turn her into the wave.
撞击力真大
Go to impulse power.
损毁报告 检查所有系统
Damage report. Checking all systems.
不是有流星雨吧 不是
That was no meteor shower. Negative,sir.
子空间震动来自323.75方位
The sub-space shock-wave originated at bearing 323.75.
位置是普拉西斯 克林冈卫星
Location... It's Praxis,sir. It's a Klingon moon.
那是他们主要的能源产地
Praxis is their key energy production facility.
发讯给克林冈指挥部说我们是星盟
Send to Klingon High Command. "This is Excelsior,a Federation Starship."
测出他们区内发生大爆炸
"We have monitored a large explosion in your sector."
问他们是否需要援助 知道
"Do you require assistance?" Aye,sir.
有其他资料吗？我确定了它的位置 但…
Mr Vultane,any more data? I've confirmed Praxis' location,but...
无法确定它的存在 放出来看
I cannot confirm Praxis' existence. On screen.
放大
Magnify. Computer enhancement.
这就是普拉西斯？对
Praxis? What's left of it,sir.
我收到普拉西斯的讯息
Captain,I'm getting a message from Praxis.
接过来
Let's have it.
我是卡拉 指挥部发言人
This is Brigadier Kerla, speaking for the High Command.
普拉西斯的确有事发生
There has been an incident on Praxis.
但一切己恢复正常 不需援助
However,everything is under control. We have no need for assistance.
遵守条约规定 别进入中立区
Obey treaty stipulations and remain outside the Neutral Zone.
通讯完毕
This transmission ends now.
有事发生？我们要报告此事吗？
An incident? Do we report this,sir?
笑话
Are you kidding?
(舰队总部)
我们为什么要来？可能是退休派对
What are we doing here? Maybe it's a retirement party.
真好 我刚买了小船
That suits me. I just bought a boat.
我本来要开学术会议
I'm supposed to be chairing a seminar at the Academy.
这是高层人员会议吗 苏路呢？
Isn't this just for top brass? Where is Sulu?
苏路有任务在身 那 史波克 呢？
Captain Sulu? On assignment. Where's Spock?
这次议程要保密 有请总司令
This briefing is classified. Ladies and gentlemen,the C-in-C.
请坐
As you were.
让我简述一下
I'll break this information down succinctly.
克林冈帝国只剩下五十年寿命
The Klingon empire has 50 years of life left.
详细情况由星盟特使交代
For full details,I'm turning this briefing over to the Federation Special Envoy.
大家早
Good morning.
我们两个月前测出普拉西斯发生爆炸
Two months ago a Federation Starship monitored an explosion on Praxis.
可能因为采矿过度及安全设施不足
We believe it was caused by over-mining and insufficient safety precautions.
卫星爆炸导致臭氧层严重污染
The moon's decimation means a deadly pollution of their ozone.
他们的氧气在五十年内就会耗尽
They will have depleted their oxygen supply in 50 Earth years.
由於军事开支太大
Due to their enormous military budget
克林冈人没有经济能力应付这场灾难
the Klingon economy doesn't have the resources to combat this catastrophe.
上月 应维冈总理要求
Last month,at the behest of the Vulcan Ambassador,
我与克林冈总理高冈对话
I opened a dialogue with Gorkon, Chancellor of the Klingon High Council.
他建议马上展开谈判
He proposes to commence negotiations at once.
谈什么？
Negotiations for what?
解散中立区的太空站
The dismantling of our space stations and bases along the Neutral Zone.
结束七十年敌对状态
An end to 70 years of hostility, which the Klingons can no longer afford.
我们要星际舰队作後备？
Bill,are we talking about mothballing the Starfleet?
这不影响我们的科学探测计划
Our exploration and scientific programs would be unaffected,but...
我一定反对
I must protest!
在星盟范围内庇护克林冈人等於自杀
To offer Klingons safe haven within Federation space is suicide.
他们会变成银河系的外星垃圾
Klingons would become the alien trash of the galaxy.
如果解散舰队
If we dismantle the fleet,
我们就无力对抗敌人
we'd be defenceless before an aggressive species on our territory.
我们一定要使他们屈服
The opportunity here is to bring them to their knees.
才能发号施令
Then we'll be in a better position to dictate terms.
长官却克船长？
Sir... Captain Kirk?
克林冈人从不可靠
The Klingons have never been trustworthy.
我同意卡上将的观点这个做法太恐布了
I agree with Admiral Cartwright. This is a terrifying idea.
当前急务是要支持高冈
It is imperative that we act now to support the Gorkon initiative,
免得克林冈的保守势力…
lest more conservative elements persuade his empire
煽动战争
that it's better to attempt a military solution and die fighting.
却克船长 你是首个和平大使
You,Captain Kirk, are to be our first olive branch.
我们要会合高冈的太空船
We are to rendezvous with the vessel which is bringing Gorkon to Earth
全程安全护送他
and to escort him safely through Federation space.
我？
Me?
你和克林冈人对和约有同感
There are Klingons who feel the same about the peace treaty as yourself,
有你指挥他们不会轻易攻击企业号
but they'll think twice about attacking the Enterprise under your command.
我私人担保你负责这项任务
I have personally vouched for you in this matter.
你私人担保？
You have personally vouched?
你要以十足外交礼节款待高冈
You will extend Chancellor Gorkon full diplomatic courtesy,Captain.
我要有经验的大使 没有其他问题的话
A full Ambassador is better equipped... If there's no further business...
我预祝你成功 散会
I wish you and your crew Godspeed. Thank you,ladies and gentlemen.
紧记这个会议要保密
I remind you this meeting is classified.
我不知应否恭喜你
I don't know whether to congratulate you or not,Jim.
我不会恭喜你
I wouldn't.
我们是自愿的？
We volunteered?
维冈人有句俗语 尼克逊才可到中国去
There's an old Vulcan proverb. "Only Nixon could go to China."
你怎能担保我？
How could you vouch for me?
那是我自作主张 我父亲要求我展开谈判
That's arrogant presumption. My father requested that I open...
我知道你父亲是维冈大使但你知道我的感受吗？
I know your father is the Vulcan Ambassador,but you know how I feel.
他们是野兽 却克
They're animals. Jim...
这是难得的机会 别相信他们
There is an historic opportunity here. Don't believe them! Don't trust them.
他们快死了 让他们自生自灭
They're dying. Let them die.
舰队叁个月内就要解散了
Has it occurred to you that this crew is due to stand down in three months?
我们一直为此而努力
We've done our bit for king and country.
你该相信我
You should have trusted me.
控制台 这是S D103接近太空码头
Control,this is S-D 103, approach to Space dock. Over.
接却克船长及队员到NCC1701
You are clear to deliver Captain Kirk and party to N.C.C. 1701 Alpha.
船长到了你是少校…
Captain on the bridge! As you were. Lieutenant?
韦利丽 我自荐做舵手的
Val'eris,sir. We were told you needed a helmsman,so I volunteered.
很高兴再见到你
It is agreeable to see you again.
她是首个维冈人高材生
She was the first Vulcan to graduate at the top of her class at the Academy.
你一定很自豪 不是
You must be very proud. I don't believe so,sir.
她是维冈人
She's a Vulcan,alright.
我们开始吧 离境站
Let's get this over with. Departure stations.
史葛 找到引擎室吗？找到了
Scotty? Did you find the engine room? Right where I left it.
准备 乌娜 替我接码头职员
Stand by. Uhura,get me the dock master.
控制台读数
Control tower reading,sir.
控制台 企业号申请离境
Control,this is Enterprise requesting permission to depart.
申请获接纳 离闸门有叁十秒
This is Control. Permission to depart granted. 30 seconds for port gates.
清除船索在此等候
Clear all moorings. Awaiting port gates from this mark.
船索清除了後推进器
All lines clear. Aft thrusters.
谢谢 要1/4动力
Thank you,Lieutenant. 1 quarter impulse power.
船长 推进器只限在码头上用
Captain,regulations specify thrusters only while in space dock.
却克…
Jim...
按指示做
You heard the order,Lieutenant.
知道
Aye,sir.
船长日志 星历98522.6
Captain's log. Stardate 9522.6.
我从不信任克林冈人
I've never trusted Klingons, and I never will.
他们害死我儿子 不能原谅
I can never forgive them for the death of my boy.
护送克林冈总理到和平高峰会
To escort the Chancellor of the Klingon High Council to a peace summit
真是棘手的工作
is problematic,at best.
史波克 说这是历史性时刻希望他对吧
Spock says this could be an historic occasion. I'd like to believe him.
但我怎能担当这历史重任？
But how on Earth can history get past people like me?
对不起你该敲门
Sorry. You could have knocked.
快到会合处了 我特来报告
We are almost at the rendezvous,sir. I thought that you would like to know.
船长 我很荣幸能为你效劳
Permission to speak freely,sir. It is an honour to serve with you.
你的太空驾驶技术不错
You piloted well out of space dock, Lieutenant.
这是我的志愿
I've always wanted to try that.
做得好
You've done well,Val'eris.
我对你的工作表现很满意
As your sponsor at the Academy I've followed your career with satisfaction.
你比我预期中还出色
And as a Vulcan, you have exceeded my expectations.
这幅画代表什么？
I do not understand this representation.
是古时地球传说的描绘
It's a depiction from ancient Earth mythology.
被逐出天堂
"The expulsion from Paradise."
为什么要挂在房里？提醒自己一切也会完
Why keep it in your quarters? To remind me that all things end.
我很想说出这个结局
It is of endings that I wish to speak.
我视你为我们族中的智者
Sir,I address you as a kindred intellect.
你察觉到…
Do you not recognise...
星盟出现转捩点吗？
that a turning point has been reached in the affairs of the Federation?
历史充满转捩点 怀着信心
History is replete with turning points. You must have faith.
信心？宇宙正在发展
Faith? The universe will unfold as it should.
合逻辑吗？我们肯定… 合逻辑…
Is that logical? Surely we must... Logic,logic,logic.
逻辑是智慧之始 不是终结
Logic is the beginning of wisdom, Val'eris. Not the end.
这是我最後一次乘太空船
This will be my final voyage on board this vessel as a member of her crew.
位置不能空着
Nature abhors a vacuum.
我想由你继任
I intend you to replace me.
我会好好接替你的工作
I could only succeed you,sir.
所有人员请到驾驶台
Now hear this. All officers to the bridge.
克林冈巡航机离开了码头所有人员请到驾驶台
Klingon battle cruiser off the port bow. All Officers to the bridge.
船长到了
Captain on the bridge!
要开防护罩吗？
Shall we raise our shields,Captain?
从未如此接近过
I've never been this close.
总理在等候指示
The Chancellor is undoubtedly awaiting our signal.
乌娜 打信号招呼 知道
Uhura,hailing frequencies. Aye,sir.
用右舵靠过去
Right standard rudder. Bring us alongside.
右舵z加5度
Right standard rudder. Z plus 5 degrees.
接通了
Channel is open,Captain.
这是企业号太空船由却克船长指挥
This is the Starship Enterprise. Captain James T. Kirk commanding.
这是卡龙诺斯一号我是高冈总理
This is Kronos One. I am Chancellor Gorkon.
我们奉命护送你到地球开会
We've been ordered to escort you to your meeting on Earth.
谢谢
Thank you.
你们想来企业号进晚餐吗？
Would you and your party care to dine this evening aboard the Enterprise
来星盟作客好吗？
as guests of the United Federation of Planets?
我们乐意接受邀请
We would be delighted to accept your gracious invitation.
我们七点半安排你们上船
We'll make arrangements to have you beamed aboard at 19:30 hours.
我热切期待
I shall look forward to that.
你满意了吧
I hope you're happy.
船长 我们有麦芽酒
Captain! There is a supply of Romulan ale aboard.
有助聚会顺利进行
It might make the evening pass more... smoothly.
好主意
Officer thinking,Lieutenant.
你猜谁会来？
Guess who's coming to dinner.
通电
Energize.
高冈总理切克船长
Chancellor Gorkon. Captain Kirk.
这是 史波克 你见过的
May I present Captain Spock, whom I believe you know.
我们终於见面了 谢谢你
Captain,face to face at last. You have my thanks.
总理
Chancellor.
各位
Gentlemen.
这是我的女儿阿惜宝
This is my daughter,Azetbur...
我的军事顾问卡拉
My military advisor,Brigadier Kerla...
这是总参谋长张上将
and this is General Chang, my chief of staff.
久仰大名
I have so wanted to meet you,Captain.
过奖了 他真的很仰慕你
I'm not sure how to take that. Sincere admiration,Kirk.
战士之间的感情
From one warrior to another.
对
Right...
请来这边参观一下
This way. You might enjoy a brief tour.
他们的长相全都差不多 还有那股气味
They all look alike. What about that smell?
只有首领才能说话
You know only top of the line models can even talk...
你们有工作做吗？有
You men have work? Yes,ma'am.
快去办事
Then snap to it.
齐来乾杯
I offer a toast.
为尚未发现的地方
The undiscovered country.
为未来为尚未发现的地方
The future. The undiscovered country.
哈姆雷特第叁幕第一场
Hamlet,act 3,scene 1.
看过克林冈文的莎士比亚才知道个中乐趣
You have not experienced Shakespeare until you've read him in Klingon.
麦芽酒不是非法的吗？
Captain Kirk. I thought Romulan ale was illegal.
离星盟总部还有一千光年没有问题
An advantage of being 1,000 light years from Federation headquarters.
敬高冈总理一杯他是我们未来的栋梁
To you,Chancellor Gorkon. One of the architects of our future.
为总理乾杯
Chancellor!
可能我们现在己看到未来
Perhaps we are looking at something of that future here.
却克 你愿放弃星际舰队吗？
Tell me,Captain Kirk. Would you be willing to give up Starfleet?
船长认为舰队做的是和平任务
The Captain feels that Starfleet's mission has always been one of peace.
我没有异议 舰队一向…
I wouldn't dispute my first officer. Starfleet has always been...
不用转弯抹角太空所有战士也很冷酷
There's no need to mince words. In space,all warriors are cold warriors.
你喜欢莎士比亚吗？
General, are you fond of... Shakespeare?
我们认为所有星球也该争取不可剥夺的人权
We believe all planets have a sovereign claim to inalienable human rights.
不可剥夺 你们只听取己见
"Inalien..." If you could only hear yourselves.
人权一词有种族歧视之意
"Human rights." Why,the very name is racist.
星盟不再是智人的专利
The Federation is a "homo sapiens only" club.
现时的同伴除外
Present company excepted,of course.
我们的文化会因此毁灭
We know where this is leading the annihilation of our culture.
不对…
That's not true. No!
做与不做是困扰我们的问题
"To be or not to be"...That is the question which preoccupies our people.
我们需要呼吸空间 地球 希特拉 1938年
We need breathing room. Earth. Hitler,1938.
你说什么？
I beg your pardon?
好了…
Well...
我们要走的路还漫长
I see we have a long way to go.
欢迎下次再来
We must do this again sometime.
你不相信我？我不怪你
You don't trust me,do you? I don't blame you.
如果有新的世界
If there is to be a brave new world,
我们的生活会十分艰难
our generation is going to have the hardest time living in it.
洗 总理 小姐
Captain Spock. Chancellor. Madam.
船长
Captain.
谢谢款待
Well,most kind.
分离真是甜蜜的悲痛
Parting is such sweet sorrow. Hmm,Captain?
听到午夜的报时钟吗？
"Have we not heard the chimes at midnight?"
谢天谢地
Thank God!
看到他们的食相吗？全无餐桌礼仪可言
Did you see the way they ate? Terrible table manners.
我们在外交史上一定很出众
I doubt our own behaviour will distinguish us in the annals of diplomacy.
我要睡了 今晚真是一团糟
I'm going to sleep this off. Is there any other way we can screw up tonight?
我要喝咖啡
I'm going to go find a pot of black coffee.
高冈总理昨晚到企业号进晚餐
The Enterprise hosted Chancellor Gorkon to dinner last night.
我们的态度不太合礼节
Our manners weren't exactly Emily Post.
通知厨房:以後的外交场合不得端上麦芽酒
To the galley Romulan ale no longer to be served at diplomatic functions.
却克 请到驾驶台找我
Captain Kirk,will you please join me on the bridge? Captain Kirk?
船长有什么事？
Captain. What is it?
我感到奇怪我很累
I find this curious. Spock,I'm really tired.
我们录得大量中子辐射
We are reading an enormous amount of neutron radiation.
在哪里？好像由我们发射
Where? It appears to emanate from us.
企业号？
The Enterprise?
韦利丽 你知道辐射激增吗？查哥夫 你呢？
Val'eris,do you know anything about a radiation surge? Chekov?
只有我的头那么大
Only the size of my head.
我明白了
I know what you mean.
发生什么事？我们射中了总理的船
What's happened? We've fired on the Chancellor's ship.
发射室 我们有否发炮？
Torpedo room! Please confirm,have we fired?
乌娜 监测一下 知道
Uhura,monitor. Aye,sir.
直接击中证实了
Direct hit. Confirmed,sir.
我们失去引力
我们被出卖了
这是驾驶台 收到吗？
This is the bridge. Do you read me?
我们有否发炮？没有 炸弹没消耗
Did we fire those torpedoes? Negative. We're still fully loaded.
找张上将
无法确定有否发炮
Unable to confirm or deny firing the torpedoes.
打信号招呼 知道
Hailing frequencies. Aye,sir.
卡龙诺斯一号这是企业号 收到吗？
Kronos One,this is Enterprise. Do you read?
情况混乱 有枪声和尖叫声
It's very hard to make out. There's been weapons firing and a lot of shouting.
船倾斜了 它失控地转
She's still listing. She's spinning out of control.
恢复後备引力
你一点气量也没有
Have you not a shred of decency in you,Kirk?
你违背了我们的和约
We come in peace, and you blatantly defy that peace.
我要你在宇宙中消失
For that, I shall blow you out of the stars.
我们没有发炮 船长…
We haven't fired. Captain...
资料库显示我们发了两炮
According to our data banks, we have. Twice...
船长 他们来了
Captain,they're coming about.
他们准备开火要开防护罩吗？
They're preparing to fire. Shields up,Captain?
防护罩要开骂？
Captain,our shields. Shields up,Captain?
发投降信号
Signal our surrender.
我们投降
We surrender!
企业号宣布投降 若他们发炮 我们没防护罩
This is Enterprise. We surrender. If they fire,with our shields down...
我们毫无还击之力 重复 企业号投降
we will not be able to respond. Repeat,Enterprise surrenders.
我们有发炮吗？我也想知道
Are we firing torpedoes? I wish I knew.
我要上船 你在此控制 我该负责 让我去吧
I'm going aboard. Spock,take the con. I involved you,I will go.
我去 总不能在和谈前夕开战
No,I'll go. We'll not be the instigators of war on the eve of universal peace.
我也去 他们需要医生
I'm going too,they may need a doctor.
乌娜 通知他们我们要上船 没有带武器
Uhura,tell them we're coming, and tell them we're unarmed.
你疯了吗？我也不知发生什么事
Have you lost your mind? ! I don't understand what's happened.
我们来帮忙的
We're here to help.
跟我来
Follow me.
高冈总理 天 发生什么事？
Chancellor Gorkon. My God! What has happened here?
你还装作无知？他怎么了？
You dare to feign ignorance? What happened?
被直接击中你破坏我们的引力系统
With a direct torpedo hit, you crippled our gravitational field
你们派来的凶手穿了磁靴
and two of your Starfleet crew beamed aboard wearing magnetic boots.
你们有医生吗？我们差不多全军覆没
Aren't you carrying a surgeon? We were until this disgrace.
让我为他急救
Then for God's sake,let me help.
他还有脉搏 来 搬他到桌上
I've got a pulse we can move him. I need light. Put him on the table.
捉紧他 我要稳定他的情况
Hold him! Hold him while I stabilize him.
捉紧他
I said hold him!
天
Sweet Jesus.
你行吗？我不清楚他的构造
Can you... I don't even know his anatomy.
他的伤口不愈合 他想杀他
His wounds are not closing. He's killing him!
他的身体机能停滞了
He's gone into some kind of damned arrest.
醒醒 醒来
Come on,dammit! Come on!
他没有反应
He's not responding.
不要就此结束
Don't let it end this way,Captain.
根据星际法例第184条
Under article 184 of your Interstellar Law...
我要拘捕你
I'm placing you under arrest.
你被控暗杀我们的总理
You're charged with assassinating the Chancellor of the High Council.
他在抢救他
He tried to save him.
他们被捕了
They've been arrested.
史波克 我们要想办法
Mr Spock,we've got to do something.
太空船自二点半开始由我指挥
I assume command of this ship as of 02:30 hours.
乌娜 通知总部 寻求对策
Commander Uhura,notify Starfleet headquarters and request instructions.
我们不能让他们进克林冈监狱
We cannot allow them to be taken to Kronos as prisoners.
开火无补於事 我们不能交战
Opening fire will not retrieve them, and we must avoid an armed conflict.
我们可追查船长的行踪
We will be able to follow the Captain's movements.
怎样追查？时间很宝贵
How did you achieve this? Time is precious.
我们要弄清今晚发生的事
We must piece together what happened here tonight.
资料库显示我们发了两次炮
According to our data bank, this ship fired those torpedoes.
没有可能 我同意 但我们需要证据
No way! I sympathize,but we need evidence.
跟我来
Please accompany me.
如果查不出问题所在呢？
And if we cannot piece together what happened? What then,sir?
那就要由外交官处理了
In that case,Mr Chekov,it resides in the purview of the diplomats.
总理死了
The Chancellor of the High Council is dead!
他受到突击
The result of an unprovoked attack
当时他在执行和平任务途中
while he travelled to see you under a flag of truce on a mission of peace!
却克船长依法被捕了
Captain Kirk was legally arrested for the crime.
他和麦盖医生登上了卡龙诺斯一号
He and Dr. McCoy boarded Kronos One of their own free will.
这是不争的事实 我己下令调查
None of these facts are in dispute. I have ordered an investigation.
同时… 同时…
In the meantime... In the meantime...
我们希望星盟遵守星际法例
we expect the Federation to abide by the articles of Interstellar Law.
却克和麦盖要为暗杀总理受审
Kirk and Dr. McCoy will stand trial for the assassination of Chancellor Gorkon.
那当然 沙力 我们可引渡他们吗？
Out of the question. Ambassador Sarek,can we get them extradited?
我对此事有一定责任
Mr President,I share a measure of personal responsibility in this matter,
但我得确认他们的法律解释
but I am obliged to confirm my esteemed colleagues legal interpretation.
罗武伦政府持什么立场？
What is the position of the Romulan government?
我同意他们的意见
I must concur with my colleagues.
难道你相信却克会暗杀总理？
You can't believe that Kirk assassinated the Chancellor of the High Council.
主席 我不知应该信什么
Mr President. I don't know what to believe.
我在等你答覆
I'm waiting for your answer,sir.
我不能凌驾於法律之上
This President is not above the law.
企业号 请回应 收到吗？
The Enterprise, please reply. Received?
我们要马上回应 我们不能离弃船长他们
We're to report back at once. We can't abandon Kirk and McCoy.
四百年前工人觉得机器有威胁性
400 years ago,on Earth,workers who felt their livelihood threatened
把凉鞋掉进机器弄停它
flung their wooden shoes called "sabots" into the machines to stop them.
这就是英文捣乱一词的由来
Hence the word "sabotage".
现在我们的後备系统坏了
We experience technical malfunction. All back-up systems inoperative.
太好了 不 真糟糕
Excellent. I mean... too bad.
我继任了父亲总理一职
Mr President,I have been named chancellor in my father's place.
总理小姐 请接受我的吊慰
Madam Chancellor, you have my condolences on your loss.
我保证那恶行不是…
I assure you that this shameful deed will not...
既然大家都想继续和谈
Let us come to the point. You want this conference to go forward.
我会在一周内出席 条件是…
I will attend in one week, on one condition.
我们不会引渡囚犯你不用营救他们
We will not extradite the prisoners, and you will not attempt to rescue them.
否则等於煽动战争
We would consider any such attempt an act of war.
我们希望你来地球作客
We hope you'll be our guest here on Earth.
经此一役 我决定保持中立
After recent events,you will understand if I prefer a neutral site.
为了安全 会面地点要保密
And in the interests of security,let us keep the location secret for now.
你作主吧
As you wish,Madam Chancellor.
趁我们有能力 快攻击他们
否则会成为他们的奴隶
动武可以占领全球
战争不合时宜
我们身处险境
我宁死也不委曲求全
这不是我父亲的遗愿
你父亲是自愿给杀死的
Your father was killed for what he wanted.
和谈要继续
The peace process will go forward.
却克…
Kirk...
却克要为我父亲偿命
Kirk will pay for my father's death.
却克…
Kirk...
不知所谓的审讯
It's a damn show trial.
企业号突击卡龙诺斯一号
The Enterprise fired on Kronos One without provocation.
总理及顾问
The Chancellor and his advisors...
当晚七点半获邀请
having been lulled into a false sense of security
到企业号用膳
by an invitation to a dinner aboard Captain Kirk's vessel
因此放松了警惕
at precisely 19:30 hours that same evening.
传第一证人
Call your first witness.
第一击後 我们失去了引力
After the first shot we lost our gravitational field.
我失控地飘起来
I was weightless and couldn't function.
两名星际舰队队员走过来
Then two Starfleet crewmen came towards me.
可能他们乔装成队员
Or perhaps they merely wore Starfleet uniforms.
这只是猜测
That remark is speculative. I move that it be stricken.
我们想听事实而非理论
We're interested in facts,not theories.
没有引力 他们如何行走？
If the gravitational unit was not functioning,how could they walk?
他们穿了磁靴
They appeared to be wearing magnetic boots.
引力靴？麦盖医生
Gravity boots? Dr. McCoy.
可否告诉我
Would you be so good as to tell me
你目前的健康状况？
what is your current medical status?
除了动脉炎外 一切正常
Aside from a touch of arthritis, I'd say pretty good.
你真有幽默感
You have a singular wit,Doctor.
我为企业号服务了二十七年
For 27 years I've been surgeon aboard the U.S.S. Enterprise.
还有叁个月就退休
In three months I stand down.
你知道吗？
You know...
我知道你当晚与众人…
I believe that you consumed rather a generous amount of Romulan ale
喝了很多麦芽酒 对吗？
in the officers mess on the night in question.
反对反对有效
Objection. Sustained.
我们全都喝了 这不表示…
We all did. All of us. That doesn't mean...
你诊断高冈总理时他还生存吗？
Was Chancellor Gorkon alive when you first examined him?
他己奄奄一息
Barely.
你以前试过救活…
Now be careful,Doctor. Have you ever in your past
与他一样垂危的病人吗？
saved patients as barely alive as he?
我不熟识克林冈人的构造
I didn't have the medical knowledge I needed for Klingon anatomy.
是吗？你也在场
I see. You where there.
你快退休了 会手震吗？
You say you are due for retirement. May I ask,do your hands shake?
反对 我很紧张
Objection! I was nervous.
不 是你无能
No. You were incompetent.
你无能
You were incompetent!
蓄意谋杀还是年老加酒精影响
Whether deliberately or as a result of age combined with drink.
法庭会判决 天 我在救他
The court will have to determine. My God,man. I tried to save him!
我尝试救他
I tried to save him.
我尽力救他
I was desperate to save him.
他是实现宇宙和平的最後希望
He was the last best hope in the Universe for peace.
证人可以退下
The witness is excused.
我们己知道案情细节
There we have it,citizens. We have established the particulars of the crime.
现在要审讯这宗悲剧的主谋
And now we come to the architect of this tragic affair.
却克船长
James Tiberius Kirk.
你最喜爱的作家会说什么？
What would your favourite author say, Captain?
坐下诉说己故国王的故事
"Let us sit upon the ground and tell sad stories of the death of kings."
说出你的故事吧
Tell us your sad story,Kirk.
说出你想怎样为子报仇
Tell us that you planned to take revenge for the death of your son.
不是这样的反对
That's not true. Objection!
没有证据显示却克船长是刺客
Captain Kirk has not been identified as the assassin.
请听听船长这番话
I offer into the record this excerpt from the Captain's personal log.
我从不信任克林冈人
I've never trusted Klingons, and I never will.
他们害死我儿子 不能原谅
I've never been able to forgive them for the death of my boy.
再放一次…
我从不信任克林冈人
I've never trusted Klingons, and I never will.
他们害死我儿子 不能原谅
I've never been able to forgive them for the death of my boy.
这是你的话吗？
Are those your words?
是我说的
Those words were spoken by me.
反对 政治立场与本案无关
Objection! My client's political views are not on trial.
他的政治立场正是关键问题
On the contrary. Captain Kirk's views are at the very heart of the matter.
记录显示他是个不守纪律
His record shows him to be an insubordinate,unprincipled opportunist
经常违抗命令的人
with a history of violating the chain of command whenever it suited him.
继绩
Continue.
却克船长曾任上将
The record shows that Captain Kirk once held the rank of Admiral
因胡作非为被降职
and he was broken for taking matters into his own hands.
难道你敢否认吗？回答我
Do you deny being demoted for these charges. Answer me now!
我不能否认 你被降职？
I cannot deny it. You were demoted?
因违抗命令？我有时不守纪律
For insubordination? On occasion,I have disobeyed orders.
你策划暗杀高冈总理时
Were you obeying or disobeying orders
是奉命行事还是违抗命令？
when you arranged the assassination of Chancellor Gorkon?
我上了船才知道他遇袭
I didn't know about it until we boarded the ship.
你仍然否认企业号向卡龙诺斯一号开火？
You still deny the Enterprise fired on Kronos One?
你仍否认派人上船射杀总理？
And you still deny your men beamed aboard and shot the Chancellor?
我不能承认或否认不知情的事
I cannot confirm or deny actions which I didn't witness.
你身为太空船船长
Are you aware that as the captain of a ship,
要为下属的行为负贵
you are responsible for the actions of your men?
我知道
I am.
若你的下属证实策划暗杀
If it's proved that members of your crew carried out the assassination...
他们在诬陷你 别回答
They're setting us up. Your Honours! Do not answer.
却克船长必须回答
Captain Kirk, you will answer the question.
身为船长…
As Captain...
我必须为下属的行为负贵
I'm responsible for the crew under my command.
群情平静了
Your Honours,the state rests.
发讯给企业号
Send to Commander Enterprise.
上进号船长苏路愿意相助
"We stand ready to assist you. Captain Sulu,U.S.S. Excelsior."
法庭裁定被告罪名成立
It is the determination of this court that the prisoners are guilty as charged.
本案证据并不充分
I wish to note for the record that all the evidence is circumstantial.
恳请法庭判刑前考虑清楚
I beg the court to consider this when pronouncing its sentence.
现在宣布
So noted.
为了保持和谈的友好气氛
Captain James T. Kirk, Dr. Leonard McCoy.
却克船长和麦盖医生
In the interest of fostering amity
法庭决定判你们死刑
for the forthcoming peace talks, the sentence of death is commuted.
这是法庭的裁决
It is the judgement of this court
没有缓刑 不能假释
that,without possibility of reprieve or parole,
你们要被放逐到劳改星球
you be taken from this place to the dilithium mines
鲁拉宾迪的矿场
on the penal asteroid of Rura Penthe.
在那里度过残生
There to spend the rest of your natural lives.
鲁拉宾迪
Rura Penthe!
银河系中的外星人坟墓
Known throughout the galaxy as the alien's graveyard.
杀了他更好 一了百了
Better to kill them now and get it over with.
请重播发炮镜头
Lieutenant. The torpedo hit once again,please.
停
Hold.
这是企业号 是我们发炮
It is Enterprise. We fired.
不可能 全部炮弹还在
That is not possible! All weapons visually accounted for,sir.
我的祖先说过
An ancestor of mine maintained
减去不可能 剩下的就是真理
that if you eliminate the impossible, whatever remains must be the truth.
什么意思？
What does that mean?
我们没有发炮 但其他人有
That if we cannot have fired those torpedoes,someone else did.
他们不会向自己开火当时又无其他船
They didn't fire on themselves and there are no other ships present.
中子曾经激增不是我们发出的
There was a neutron surge. Not from us.
促由另一艘船发出
A neutron surge that big could only be produced by another ship.
卡龙诺斯一号？太远了
Kronos One? Too far away.
很接近我们 可能在我们下面
Very near us. Possibly beneath us.
如果下面有船 他们定会看见
If there were a ship beneath us, the Klingons would have seen it.
会吗？
Would they?
猛禽号？猛禽号
A Bird of Prey? A Bird of Prey.
隐了形？隐形怎能开火
Cloaked? They can't fire when they're cloaked.
正常情况下是不可能
All things being equal,I would agree.
但此事很不寻常 或许有可能
However,things are not equal. This one can.
我们要通知司令 通知什么？
We must inform Starfleet Command. Of what?
有新隐形武器？他们一定说我们疯了
A new weapon that's invisible? They'll call us raving lunatics.
说我们为了救船长什么也敢说
They'll say we'll say anything to exonerate the Captain.
他们说得对 我们没有证据
And they would be correct. We have no evidence.
只有切合现实的理论
Only a theory which happens to fit the facts.
他们为何要杀自己的总理？
Assuming you're right. Why would they fire on their own President?
真是
Indeed.
要彻底搜索这艘船
This ship will be searched from bow to stern.
我不明白 如果有船在下面
I do not understand. If there was a ship underneath us
炮弹不会从这里发出
surely the assassins beamed aboard from that vessel,not Enterprise.
你忘了一件事
You're forgetting something, Mr Chekov.
资料库显示我们发了炮
According to our data banks, this ship fired those torpedoes.
凶手应该在这里
If we did,the killers are here.
改动资料库的人也在这里
If we did not, whoever altered the data banks is here.
我们要在此搜寻
In either case, what we are looking for is here.
搜寻什么？你认为呢？
What are we looking for,sir? Lieutenant.
两双引力靴
Two pairs of gravity boots.
这里就是劳改星球鲁拉宾迪
This is the gulag Rura Penthe.
没有监狱  守卫塔  电子边界
There is no stockades,no guard tower,no electronic frontier.
只有磁力罩
Only a magnetic shield prevents beaming.
若有犯错 刑罚是逐上地面
Punishment means exile from prison to the surface.
没有人能在地面生存
On the surface,nothing can survive.
做好点 待遇会好点
Work well,and you will be treated well.
做得不好 就会死
Work badly,and you will die.
天
Oh,my God!
我们没有翻译员
The universal translator has been confiscated.
什么？
I'm sorry?
他有话想说
He's definitely on about something,Jim.
如果这是你的范围 我们会走
If this is your spot,we'll move on.
他要你服从外星人公会
He wants your obedience to the Brotherhood of Aliens.
没问题交出你的外套
He's got it. And your coat.
恐怕不称身
I'm afraid not. It wouldn't fit.
谢谢 这有助你保暖
Thanks. This will help keep you warm.
我是马蒂亚 我知你们是谁 你怎知道？
I'm Martia. You're Kirk and McCoy. How did you know that?
你们暗杀总理
We don't get many presidential assassins.
我们没有杀高冈 当然没有
We didn't kill Gorkon. Of course not.
但判你死刑有奖赏 有道理
But there's a reward for your death. That figures.
我们被诬陷
We've been set up.
有人不想你们碍事
Somebody up there wants you out of the way.
有何进展？没有
Any progress? None.
有叁百人展开搜索但凶手也可能在其中
A crew of 300 are looking everywhere,but the killers may still be among them.
磁靴肯定己丢掉了
Surely they have disposed of these boots by now.
靴子会否留在高冈的船上
Would it not have been logical to leave them on Gorkon's ship?
他们离开时引力还未恢复
Logic must give way to physics. Gravity wasn't restored when they escaped.
没有磁靴就会浮起
Without the boots,they would have floated off the transporter pads.
何不直接把它化掉？
Why not simply vaporize them?
这样？
Like this?
不能未经许可在船上开死光枪
As you know,no one can fire an unauthorized phaser aboard a starship.
可能他们回来时扔掉靴子
Suppose,when they returned,they threw the boots into the refuse.
我正搜寻垃圾堆
I'm having the refuse searched.
我猜凶手把靴挂在颈上
If I'm correct,those boots will cling to the killer's necks like Tiberian bats.
他们不能不穿靴离去也不能抛出窗外
They couldn't escape without them nor throw them out the window.
靴子一定在这里某处
Those boots are here. Somewhere.
有人开枪吗？没事
Did someone fire off a phaser? It's alright. It's nothing.
星际舰队催促我们回码头
Mr Spock,Starfleet is screaming for us to return to port.
谁发射…史葛
Who fired the... Ah,Mr Scott.
听说船索坏了 要修理多久？
I hear you have difficulty with the warp drive. How long do you need for repair?
船索那有问题？
There's nothing wrong with the bloody thing.
若我们回去 凶手会丢掉靴子
If we return to space dock,the killers can dispose of their footwear
我们无缘再见船长和麦盖了
and we will never see the Captain or Dr. McCoy alive again.
需要几星期 谢谢
It could take weeks. Thank you.
通知舰队我们的船索失灵
Val'eris,inform Starfleet our warp drive is inoperative.
这是谎话？只是差错
A lie? An error.
我们跟船长和麦盖完全失去联络
We have lost all contact with the Captain and Dr. McCoy.
现在他们被磁罩包围
Yes,at the moment they're surrounded by a magnetic shield.
我猜船长一定在计划逃狱
But if I know the Captain,he is deep into planning his escape.
却克 你触怒了他
You've got him where you want him,Jim!
你没事吧？没事
Are you alright? I think so.
你现在受到尊重了 幸好那东西有膝盖
They'll respect you now. I was lucky that thing had knees.
那不是他的膝盖
That was not his knee.
每个人的生殖部位都不一样
Not everybody keep their genitals in the same place,Captain.
你是说…
Anything you want to tell me?
快去解释我们无意冒犯
See what you can do for him. Let him know we're not holding a grudge.
他可能很生气
Suppose he's holding a grudge?
不论人们做什么 也不要多问
When whoever it is makes their move,you won't be here to ask if he's the one.
你想逃出去吗？一定有出路的
Do you want to get out of here? There's got to be a way.
退休前叁个月就完蛋了
Three months before retirement. What a way to finish.
我们还未完蛋 你自圆其说
We're not finished. Speak for yourself.
迟早会完的
One day,one night... Kobayashi Maru!
你害怕将来吗？
Bones! Are you afraid of the future?
这正是我一直想说的事
I believe that was the general idea that I was trying to convey.
我不是指这个将来 是什么？选择题？
I don't mean this future. What is this multiple choice?
有些人害怕将会发生的事
Some people are afraid... of what might happen.
我很怕你怕什么？
I was terrified. What terrified you,specifically?
再没有中立区
No more Neutral Zone.
我一向憎恨克林冈人
I was used to hating Klingons.
我从不信高冈所言
It never even occurred to me to take Gorkon at his word.
史波克 对了 别自贵 我们同样难受
Spock was right. We all felt exactly the same.
不 有人难受得多
No. Somebody felt a lot worse.
我开始明白了
I'm beginning to understand why.
若你没有好主意现在是时候…
If you've got any bright ideas,now is the time.
时间是问题 我们帮不上忙
Time is the problem. You and I are nothing.
你听到吗？和谈恢复了
You heard the judge the peace conference is on again.
杀高冈的凶手会再进行暗杀
Whoever killed Gorkon is bound to attempt another assassination.
除非我们逃离这里
Unless we can get out of here.
是我 没有人曾成功逃狱
It's me Martia. Listen. No one has ever escaped from Rura Penthe.
除了我们 有可能的
Except us. It is possible.
我知道如何逃出罩外
I know how to get outside the shield.
我们要怎样做？出去其实很容易
How do we fit in? Getting outside the shield is easy.
但要在冻僵前逃出生天
After that,you have to get us off the surface before we freeze. Can you?
没问题 我需要你帮忙
It's possible. I can't make it alone.
你是最有潜质的候选人
You're the likeliest candidate to come here for months.
什么候选人？
Candidate for what?
早上采矿时在7号电梯见
Go to lift 7 in the morning for mining duty. I'll see you there.
别令我失望
Don't disappoint me.
你怎么了？还认为我们会完蛋吗
What is it with you,anyway? Still think we're finished?
从未如此担心过
More than ever.
吵醒你真对不起
Sorry to wake you,sir.
星际舰队想知道企业号的位置
Starfleet requests any data we have on the whereabouts of Enterprise.
什么？
What?
他们拒绝确认回码头的信号
They're refusing to acknowledge signal to return to space dock,sir.
回覆说我们不知企业号的位置
Signal Starfleet that we have no idea location Enterprise.
船长？你听觉有问题吗？
Sir? You have hearing problems?
没有
No,sir.
克林冈人的血
Klingon blood.
肯定是他们把血迹踩了进来
They must have walked through it when it was floating and tracked it back here.
这是我们的第一证据
This is the first evidence which corroborates our theory.
要通知星际舰队吗？
Now we go to Starfleet?
现在连制服也要搜查
We expand our search to include uniforms.
所有制服？
All uniforms?
这里没有
Clear,sir. Make a hole.
请让开
Coming through. Coming through.
船长…
Sir! Sir!
她欺骗我们 你没有被骗
I think we've been had. No,you weren't,Doctor.
在第一层离去 跟大队到矿场
Get off at the first level. Follow the gang into the mine.
他们不载女孩
They don't take girls.
你是迪斯？对 什么事
You are crewman Dax? Yes. What is the problem?
听过灰姑娘的故事吗？
Perhaps you know the Russian epic of Cinderella?
试试是否合穿
If shoe fits wear it.
查哥夫…
Mr Chekov...
看我的
Watch me.
这是什么生物？昨晚你们… 别提了
What kind of creature is this? Last night you two were...
进来
Get in.
快 我们时间无多
Come on. We don't have a lot of time.
快点
Hurry!
上面
Up there.
来 爬上来
Come on climb!
穿上这些 快
Here,you'll need these. Quickly!
跟我来
Stay close.
他们在这里 他们快逃出来了
There they are. They emerge from the beaming shield.
史葛 开动引擎查哥夫 驶往鲁拉宾迪
Mr Scott,start your engines. Mr Chekov,set course for Rura Penthe.
鲁拉宾迪在克林冈边境内深处
Mr Spock,Rura Penthe is deep inside the Klingon frontier.
若我们发现… 对
If we're discovered... Correct.
在船长和麦盖冻死前
We need a feat of linguistic legerdemain and intrepidity
我们要运用掩眼法和勇气
before the Captain and Dr. McCoy freeze to death.
别理我 我完了 不会的
Leave me,I'm finished. No!
我身上有追踪器
Bones,I'm wearing a viridium patch on my back.
史波克 在我们上船前贴上
Spock slapped it there before we went on Gorkon's ship.
这个狡猾的维冈人
That cunning little Vulcan.
来 我们安全了
Come on! We're in the clear.
我们在罩外他们可追踪到我们
Now that we're outside the shield,they can locate us two sectors away.
如果他们在找我们的话
If they're even looking for us.
这是莫斯卡短波电台
这是什么船？
我们要回应 需要翻译
We must respond. A universal translator would be recognised.
我们是你的货船厄斯华
离开了卡龙诺斯
六星期
你们往什么目的地？
"What is your destination,over?"
我们有食物
物资供应
别捉虫子
可否解释一下你的把戏？
Would you mind explaining that little trick you do?
我是金密莱人 我听过这名字
I'm a Chameloid. I've heard about you.
变形人 真神奇
Shape-shifters. I thought you were mythical.
船长 给女孩一个机会
Give a girl a chance,Captain.
很费劲的
It takes a lot of effort.
我同意
I don't doubt it.
如果我错了 请告诉我
Stop me if I'm wrong,
那一个才是真正的你？
but do we have any way of knowing whether this is the real you?
我采用了吸引人的形象
I thought I would assume a pleasing shape.
我们己逃脱 到你了
We're outside the shield. Now it's your turn,Captain.
这个…
If you say so.
你疯了吗？
Are you crazy? !
她不需我们帮助你的便服从何来的？
She didn't need our help. Where did you get these convenient clothes?
那火光不是监中物件
Don't tell me that flare is standard prison issue.
她在通风报信 换取报酬
It's to let them know where we are. Ask her what she's getting in return.
你竟然这样对我
A full pardon... which doesn't cover this.
这不可能是意外
An accident wasn't good enough. Come on,Spock.
次意外没有问题 两次会惹人怀疑
Good enough for one. Two would have looked suspicious.
逃亡时被杀 双方也可信
Killed while attempting escape. That's convincing for both.
意外吧
Surprise!
你的朋友来迟了 他们正赶来
Your friends are late. They'll be along.
我竟然吻过你 你一定期待己久
I can't believe I kissed you. Must have been your lifelong ambition.
你是时候改变形象了
Isn't it time you became something else?
我喜欢这个形象
I like it here.
好了…
Well,well,well...
你为何来得这么晚？
What took you so long?
杀了他 他才是真身
Kill him,he's the one.
不是我 是他
Not me,you idiot him!
没有证人逃亡时被杀
No witnesses. Killed while trying to escape.
真聪明这是经典
Damned clever,if you ask me. It's a classic.
这是他们的意思 谁？谁想杀我们？
That's what he wanted. Who? Who wanted us killed?
反正你要死 告诉你又何妨
Since you're all going to die anyway,why not tell you?
他是…
His name is...
真讨厌…你为何不多等两秒？
Damn it! What the hell! Son of a... Couldn't you have waited two seconds?
他正交代事情始末
He was about to explain the whole thing.
你想回去？绝对不
You want to go back? Absolutely not!
这是驾驶台 我们仍在克林冈领空
This is the bridge. We're still in Klingon space.
9号甲板 维持战斗岗位
Deck 9,remain at battle stations. Deck 9,remain at battle stations.
他们被接回星盟太空船
我可以追踪…
逃脱
却克不知道和谈的场地
你肯定？
你愿意冒险吗？
舵手 快去拦截企业号
克林冈人有艘猛禽号可以隐形发炮
The Klingons have a Bird of Prey that can fire while cloaked.
它向高冈的船发炮 就是它
She torpedoed Gorkon's ship. So that's it.
凶手就在这艘船上
We believe that Gorkon's murderers are aboard this ship.
和谈开始了没有？不知道 地点保密
Has the peace conference begun? Who knows? The location is secret.
一定有事船长 史波克
There's always something. Captain! Mr Spock!
我发现染有克林冈人血迹的制服
I found the uniforms with the Klingon blood on them.
制服属於这两个人卜奇和沉努
But the uniforms belong to these two men. Burke and Samno.
有人近距离向他们开枪
Not anymore. Phaser on "stun" at close range.
暗杀规例第一条:杀死刺客
First rule of assassination kill the assassins.
我们退回起点了 我想和你谈谈
Now we're back to square one. Can I talk to you?
他们为何没有化掉 会惊动警钟
Why weren't they vaporized? It would set off the alarm.
这也可行
It's possible.
请注意…
Now hear this. Now hear this.
速记员请到病房 蓝色急事
Court reporter to sick bay. Code blue urgent.
急需录取卜奇和沉努的口供
Statements to be taken at once from Yeomen Burke and Samno.
速记员请到病房 蓝色急事
Repeat,court reporter to sick bay. Code blue urgent.
要录取口供
Statements to be taken.
录取卜奇和沉努的口供
Repeat,statements to be taken from Yeomen Burke and Samno.
你应该开枪
You have to shoot.
你有逻辑的话 就应该开枪
If you are logical,you have to shoot.
我不想的 你的目的毫无意义
I do not want to. What you want is irrelevant.
你的选择已经得到
What you've chosen is at hand.
我不希望是你
I'd just as soon you didn't.
手术完了
The operation is over.
我没有发炮 你没有证据
I did not fire. You cannot prove anything.
审讯时 我的日志成为证物
Yes,I can. At my trial my personal log was used against me.
你一直在我房外探听
How long did you wait outside my quarters before I noticed you?
你知道？
You knew?
我想告诉你 但你不听
I tried to tell you,but you would not listen.
当晚没有人留心听
Neither of us was hearing very well that night.
我曾叫你要有信心
There were things I tried to tell you,about having faith.
你们全部也背叛了星盟
You have betrayed the Federation. All of you.
你认为自己在做什么 拯救星际舰队
And what have you've been doing? Saving Starfleet.
克林冈人不可靠船长 你说过的
Klingons cannot be trusted. Sir... You said so yourself.
他们杀了你的儿子你不想高冈死吗？
They killed your son. Did you not wish Gorkon dead?
你说过 让他们自生自灭
"Let them die",you said. Did I misinterpret you?
你说对了
And you were right.
他们与我们串通暗杀自己的总理
They conspired with us to assassinate their own Chancellor.
他们怎会可信？
How trustworthy can they be?
克林冈人与星盟成员串通
Klingons and Federation members conspiring together.
谁是"我们"？不爱和平的人
Who is "us"? All who stands to lose from peace.
说出他们的名字
Names,Lieutenant.
我的同党会干扰你们的通讯
My comrades will make certain all your transmissions are jammed.
说出他们的名字 我记不起
Names,Lieutenant! I do not remember.
这是谎话？
A lie?
只是选择
A choice.
史波克
Spock.
卡上将
Admiral Cartwright.
来自星际舰队？
From Starfleet?
还有谁？
Who else?
张上将
General... Chang.
还有呢？罗武伦大使及其他人
Who else? Romulan Ambassador and others.
和谈在哪里举行？
Where is the peace conference?
她不知道
She does not know.
那我们死了
Then we're dead.
我己死过一次 联络上进号
I have been dead before. Contact Excelsior.
他们会提供合作 我己联络了他
She'll have the co-ordinates. I've already got it,sir.
却克船长 准备 苏路
Standing by,Captain Kirk. Sulu.
你知否我们通话是违反规条？
You realize that by even talking to us,you're violating regulations.
对不起 我听不清楚
I'm sorry,Captain. Your message is breaking up.
和谈在哪里举行？
Bless you,Sulu. Where is the peace conference?
他们会发动第二次暗杀
They'll attempt another assassination.
杰图马营 罗武伦边境附近
It's at Camp Khitomer,near the Romulan border.
我会用密码信号发给你
I'm sending the co-ordinates on a coded frequency.
恐怕这还不够
We'll need more than that.
我们被猛禽号监视它可以隐形发炮
There's a Bird of Prey on the look-out for us that can fire while cloaked.
不是吧
Surely not.
有多少人在那里？
How many of those things are there? Come on,Lieutenant.
只有样本你听到吗？
Just the prototype. Do you hear that?
我现在起航 但我们郧脍一区
I'm getting under way now. We're in Alpha Quadrant.
恐怕赶不及到会场
The chances of our reaching the conference in time are slim.
会议何时开始？我收到的资料是今天
When does this conference start? According to my information today.
谢谢你 别客气
Thank you,Captain Sulu. Don't mention it,Captain Kirk.
史波克 ？
Spock?
不要开灯
I prefer it dark.
你在忏悔？对
Dining on ashes? You were right.
都怪我自视过高
It was arrogant presumption on my part that got us into this situation.
你和麦盖差点没命
You and the Doctor might have been killed.
我们经验不够
The night is young.
你说为了和平 值得犯险
You said it yourself,it was logical. Peace is worth a few personal risks.
你有逻辑头脑
You're a great one for logic.
我则好管闲事
I'm a great one for rushing in where angels fear to tread.
我们太激进 该学习中庸之道
We're both extremists. Reality is probably somewhere in between.
我不能忘掉丧子之痛
I couldn't get past the death of my son.
她的出色表现令我偏爱
I was prejudiced by her accomplishments as a Vulcan.
高冈死了我才知道自己十分偏激
Gorkon had to die before I understood how prejudiced I was.
是不是…
Is it possible...
我们又老又不灵活
that we two,you and I,have grown so old and inflexible
什么也做不来了？
that we have outlived our usefulness?
这是不是笑话？
Would that constitute a joke?
这不是你的错 我有责任
It wasn't your fault. I was responsible.
只需为自己的行为负责 你在庭上不是这样说
For no actions but your own. That's not what you said at your trial.
身为船长 作为人…
That was as captain of the ship. Human beings...
你该知道我不是人
We both know that I am not human.
你知道吗？众生也是人
Do you want to know something? Everybody's human.
我觉得这句话很侮辱
I find that remark... insulting.
来 我需要你
Come,I need you.
总理小姐 各位外交人员
Madam Chancellor,members of the diplomatic corps...
各位来宾
honoured guests.
星盟欢迎你们来到杰图马营
The United Federation of Planets welcomes you to Camp Khitomer.
猛禽号一定在附近
She's out here somewhere.
如果它隐了形 唯有看辐射读数
But if she's cloaked... Then all we have is a radiation surge.
我们录得辐射时 已经炸死了
By the time we're close enough to record it,we're ashes.
2.06…
2.06
2.03…
2.03
可以起程了吗？还有两分钟 1.58
Close enough to beam down? Not yet. In two minutes. 1.58.
全速驶往杰图马营
Go to impulse power for Khitomer.
我们有能力做一件事
Let us redefine progress to mean that just because we can do a thing
不代表我们一定要去做
it does not necessarily follow that we must do that thing.
邬娜？没有异像
Uhura? Nothing,Captain.
猛禽号可能正在无声航行
If she's here,she's rigged for silent running.
还有57秒到达运送器范围
Coming up on transporter range in 57 seconds.
运送器房 准备
Transporter room. Stand by to beam down.
53秒
53...
48秒
48 seconds.
44秒
44...
却克 我看到你了
I can see you,Kirk.
张上将
Chang.
你看到我吗？
Can you see me?
老实说 战士对战士
Now be honest,Captain. Warrior to warrior.
你喜欢这样的 是吗？
You do prefer it this way,don't you? As it was meant to be.
我们这里没有和平
No peace in our time.
好朋友 进攻又开始了
"Once more unto the breach,dear friends."
真有趣 回动引擎 退後
This is fun. Reverse engines. All astern.
以1.5冲力退後
One and a half impulse power. Back off!
它做什么？
它在等什么？
What's she waiting for?
可能想知道我们为何退後
Probably attempting to ascertain why we are reversing.
看我们是否侦察到它
Wondering whether we detect her.
来了
Incoming!
相通了吗？还未
In range? Not yet,sir.
快点
Come on!
它会爆炸的 那就炸掉它
She'll fly apart. Fly her apart,then!
很多人也怀疑我父亲的动机
Many speculated about my father's motives.
有人说他是空想家有人说他没有选择
Some said he was an idealist. Others said he had no choice.
如果普拉西斯不爆炸他不会有此空想
If Praxis had not exploded,his idealism wouldn't have found expression.
我们以自己的民族为荣
We are a proud race.
我们想继续感到自豪
We are here because we intend to go on being proud.
启动後备电力 後备电路受到破坏
Go to auxiliary power! Auxiliary circuits destroyed.
痒了可以不笑吗？刺伤了可以不流血吗
"Tickle us,do we not laugh? Prick us,do we not bleed?"
遭到欺负可以不报复吗？
"Wrong us,shall we not revenge?"
气
Gas.
船在冲力下要加气
Gas,Captain. Under impulse power she expands fuel,like all vessels.
要离子气
We call it "plasma", but it is merely ionised gas.
记录气体反常的设备呢？
What about our equipment to catalogue gaseous anomalies?
那一定有排气管
The thing's got to have a tail-pipe.
医生 可否为飞弹做手术？
Doctor,would you assist me in performing surgery on a torpedo?
好
Fascinating.
转右
Hard to starboard.
我们建议在地球时间五十年内
The proposed agenda is as follows: The evacuation of Kronos
撤走我们的居民
has been calculated within the 50 Earth year time span.
第一阶段:准备撤走…
Phase 1 preparation for evacuation...
我们受到猛击 防护罩受损
Captain,she's packing quite a wallop. Shields weakening.
开防护罩 等待他们进攻
Shields up! Alright,now we're giving them something else to shoot at.
游戏还未结束
The game's afoot.
上进号被击中了 游戏结束了
Excelsior's been hit! "Our revels now are ended", Kirk.
大混乱 我要发动战争
"Cry havoc,and let slip the dogs of war."
我的飞弹呢 不用操心
Bones,where's my torpedo? Bet you wished you'd stayed in bed.
防护罩塌下了
Shields collapsing!
拿钥匙来 时间无多
The key,please. Time is short.
船身被击中 不知损毁隋况如何？
The hull has been compromised. I wonder how bad.
接上回波棒
Connect echo-bars.
讨论第二阶段的报告
discuss the report on phase 2.
更改A电路 探测器
Alter circuit A. Sensor.
开始看计划的议程
we commence within minutes of the preparation.
我像北极星般不败 他闭嘴的话 我给他钱
"I am constant as the Northern star." I'd give real money,if he'd shut up.
拿板来
Plate,please.
同化要花费…
and assimilation will consume...
有反应了
We've got a heart beat.
克林冈帝国…
with the Klingon Empire...
钥匙
Key,please.
飞弹呢？准备好了
Where's that torpedo? She's ready.
准备发射
Lock and load!
发射
Fire!
做还是…
"To be... or not"...
不做
"to be."
瞄准它开火
Target that explosion and fire.
发射
Fire!
这项工作需时一星期
This work will occupy us throughout most of the week.
希望代表团
I hope that the delegation
下月前履行第一阶段的规定
can implement the provisions of Phase 1 by the first of next month.
时间是关键
As you know,time is of the essence.
让开
Out of the way!
主席
Mr President!
我是企业号的却克
Kirk,Enterprise.
保护总理
拘捕他们 拘捕你自己
Arrest those men! Arrest yourself!
她己彻底招供
We've got a full confession.
这不是克林冈人的血 卡上将 别逃
This is not Klingon blood. Cartwright. Just a minute.
什么事？这是怎么一回事？
What's happened? What's the mean of all of this?
有关未来的事
It's about the future,Madam Chancellor.
有人认为未来代表历史的终结
Some people think the future means the end of history.
但历史还未完结
We haven't run out of history quite yet.
你的父亲称未来为…
Your father called the future...
尚未发现的地方
"The undiscovered country".
人人都害怕转变
People can be very frightened of change.
你重建了我父亲的信心
You've restored my father's faith.
你重建了我儿子的信心
And you've restored my son's.
我们再一次挽救了文明
Once again,we've saved civilization as we know it.
幸好他们不起诉我们
And they're not going to prosecute.
我或会像韦利丽一样遭起诉
They could have prosecuted me. I felt like Val'eris.
不会的
They don't arrest people for having feelings.
真好 否则我们会有麻烦
And it's a good thing,too. If they did,we'd all have to turn ourselves in.
切克船长 苏路船长
Captain Kirk. Captain Sulu.
我代表所有船员向你致谢
As much to the crew of the Enterprise,I owe you my thanks.
很高兴再次与你合作 保重
Nice to see you in action one more time,Captain Kirk. Take care.
天 真是艘大船 但也不及船长伟大
My God,that's a big ship. Not so big as her captain.
这是再见了？
So... This is goodbye?
我们是时候各自启航
It's about time we got underway ourselves.
星际舰队有令
Captain,I have orders from Starfleet Command.
马上返回太空码头 解散队伍
We're to put back to space dock immediately... to be decommissioned.
如果我是人 我的反应会是…
If I were human,I believe my response would be:
去死吧
"Go to hell."
如果我是人的话
If I were human.
要驶向哪里？
Course heading,Captain?
右面第二个星球
Second star to the right.
直驶至明早
And straight on 'til morning.
掏吕长日志 星历9529.1
Captain's log,stardate 9529.1.
这是企业号最後一次在我指挥下航行
This is the final cruise of the Starship Enterprise under my command.
这艘船和它的历史
This ship,and her history
很快会由另一队伍接管
will shortly become the care of another crew.
我们把未来交给後世的人们
To them and their posterity will we commit our future.
他们会继续我们的旅程
They'll continue the voyages we have begun
探索所有尚未到过的地方
and journey to all the undiscovered countries
勇敢地到没有人…
boldly going where no man,where no one...
到过的地方
has gone before.